intellectualtakeout.org 2019-12-26

# Intellectual Takeout Privacy Policy | Intellectual Takeout

Protecting personal information is important to Intellectual Takeout.  It is the policy of Intellectual Takeout to protect the confidentiality of e-mail addresses and other personal information that we receive or collect in the course of our activities. We secure the confidentiality of such information through various means, including physical, electronic, and administrative safeguards that are designed to protect against unauthorized access. It is our policy to limit access to personal information to that which is lawful and to prohibit unlawful disclosure of personal information.

**Introduction**

We are very sensitive to privacy issues. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to let you know how we handle the information we receive from you through the Intellectual Takeout website. Portions of the Intellectual Takeout website may describe additional privacy practices applicable to specific types of information or to information provided on specific website pages.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to information collected through other means such as by telephone or in person, although that information may be protected by other privacy policies. As used in this Privacy Policy, terms such as “we” or “our” and the “Organization” refer to Intellectual Takeout, a Minnesota nonprofit corporation and its current and future affiliates.

The Intellectual Takeout website is intended for a United States audience. If you access the website from outside the U.S., you acknowledge, agree, and consent that any information you provide, including any personal information, will be transferred to and processed by a computer server located within the U.S., and subject to U.S. laws and regulations. Further, if you access this site from outside the U.S., you acknowledge and agree that you are responsible for compliance with any applicable local or national laws, rules or regulations applicable to such use.

**Cookies and non-personal information**

“Non-personal information” means information that does not permit us to specifically identify you by your full name or similar unique identifying information such as a social security number, e-mail address, postal address or telephone number. We use “cookie” technology and similar technology to gather non-personal information from our website visitors such as which pages are used and how often they are used, and to enable certain features on the Intellectual Takeout website.

 You may disable these cookies and similar items by adjusting your browser preferences on your computer at any time; however, this may limit your ability to take advantage of all the features on the Intellectual Takeout website. Keep in mind that cookies are not used to collect any personal information and do not tell us who you are.  Some examples of the way we use cookies include:

  * Tracking resources and data accessed on the website.
  * Recording general website statistics and activity.
  * Assisting users experiencing website problems.
  * Enabling certain functions and tools on the website.
  * Tracking paths of visitors to the website and within the website.

We may also collect other forms of non-personal information such as what web browsers are used to read our website and what websites are referring traffic or linking to our website. Aggregate and de-identified data regarding website users is also considered non-personal information.

**With whom is non-personal information shared?**

Because non-personal information does not identify who you are, we do not limit the ways we may use or share non-personal information. For example, we may share non-personal information with our affiliates, suppliers, employees and agents, and other businesses and organizations.

**Personal information provided by you**

“Personal information” means information that specifically identifies you as an individual, such as your full name, telephone number, e-mail address, postal address, or certain account numbers.  The Intellectual Takeout website may include web pages that give you the opportunity to provide us with personal information about yourself. **You do not have to provide us with personal information if you do not want to; however, that may limit your ability to participate in certain activities such as petitions, polls or surveys or use certain functions of the website or to request certain services or information**. We may combine personal information that you provide us through the Intellectual Takeout website with other personal information held by the Organization, our affiliates or our vendors.  

We may use personal information for a number of purposes such as:

  * To respond to an e-mail or particular request from you.
  * To personalize the website for you.
  * To process an application as requested by you.
  * To provide you with information that we believe may be useful to you, such as information about products or services provided by us or by other organizations or businesses.
  * To comply with applicable laws, regulations, and legal process.
  * To protect someone's health, safety, or welfare.
  * To protect our rights, the rights of affiliates or related third parties, or take appropriate legal action.
  * To keep a record of our transactions and communications.
  * As otherwise necessary or useful for us to conduct our business, so long as such use is permitted by law.

You understand and specifically agree that we may use personal information to contact you through any contact information you provide through the Intellectual Takeout website, including any e-mail address, postal address, telephone number, cell phone number, text message number, or fax number.

**With whom is personal information shared?**

We will only share your personal information with third parties as outlined in this Privacy Policy (in its current or future form) and as otherwise permitted by law.

We share and give access to personal information to our employees and agents in the course of conducting our activities. For example, if you sent us an e-mail message asking a question, we may provide your e-mail address to one of our employees or agents, together with your question, in order for that person to reply to your question. We may share personal information with other affiliates or divisions within the Organization.

We may share and give access to personal information with other companies that we hire to perform services on our behalf or with whom we collaborate.  For example, we may hire an outside company to help us send and manage e-mail, and in that case we might provide the outside company with your e-mail address and certain other information in order for them to send you an e-mail message on our behalf. Similarly, we may hire outside companies to host or operate some of our websites and related computers and software applications.

However, if we share or give access to personal information to outside companies we require them to use the personal information only for limited purposes, such as for sending you the e-mail in the example above. If you believe we or any company associated with the Organization has misused any of your personal information, please contact us immediately and report such misuse.

We may share personal information if all or part of the Organization is sold, merged, dissolved, acquired, or transferred in a similar transaction.

 We may share personal information in response to a court order, subpoena, search warrant, law or regulation.  We may cooperate with law enforcement authorities in investigating and prosecuting website visitors who violate our rules, or engage in behavior that is harmful to other visitors, or is illegal.

If you submit information, comments or other posting on the Intellectual Takeout website, the information you submit, together with your screen name, will be visible to all visitors, and such visitors may share with others. Therefore, please be thoughtful in what you write and understand that this information may become public.

**Special Notice to California Residents**

Under the California Civil Code, California residents who provide to us any personal information (as such term is defined under California law) have the right to request from us once each calendar year a list of all third parties to which we have disclosed personal information (as so defined) during the preceding calendar year for such third parties’ own direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident and wish to obtain this information, please send an email request to us at _[contact@intellectualtakeout.org](mailto:contact@intellectualtakeout.org)_ with a statement of your preference on how you wish to receive our response to your request. Please note that not all information sharing is covered by the California Civil Code requirements and that only covered information, if any, will be included in our response.

Under the California Business and Professions Code, we are required to disclose how we respond to web browser “Do Not Track” signals or other mechanisms that provide consumers with the ability to exercise choice regarding the collection of personally identifiable information (as such term is defined under California law) about a consumer’s online activities. We do not currently respond to or otherwise take any action with regard to “Do Not Track” requests.

**Reviewing your information**

The Intellectual Takeout website may permit you to view your visitor profile and related personal information. If this function is available, we will include a link on the website with a heading such as “My Profile” or similar words. Clicking on the link will take you to a page through which you may review your visitor profile and related personal information.

**Website and information security**

We use a number of physical and electronic security methods (such as locks and alarm systems, passwords and encryption), and procedural security methods (such as rules regarding the handling and use of information), designed to protect the security and integrity of information submitted through the Intellectual Takeout website. Due to the nature of the Internet and online communications, however, we cannot guarantee that any information transmitted online will remain absolutely confidential, and we are not liable for the illegal acts of third parties such as criminal hackers.

**Our online communication practices**

_General e-mail communications_

Most e-mail, including any e-mail functionality on the Intellectual Takeout website, does not provide a completely secure and confidential means of communication. It is possible that your e-mail communication may be accessed or viewed inappropriately by another Internet user while in transit to us. If you wish to keep your information completely private, you should not use e-mail. We may send e-mail communications to you on topics of interest.

_Other online communications_

The Organization may send electronic newsletters, notification of account status, and other communications such as information marketing other products or services offered by us, on a periodic basis to various individuals and organizations. To opt-out of any specific electronic communication you are receiving, click on the opt-out button associated with the specific communication.

**Information for children under 13**

We will not intentionally collect any personal information from children under the age of 13 through the Intellectual Takeout website without receiving verifiable parental consent. If you think that we have collected personal information from a child under the age of 13 through the website, please contact us.

**Contact us**

To contact us regarding this Privacy Policy and our related privacy practices, [visit the Contact Us page](http://www.unitedhealthgroup.com/main/ContactUs.aspx).

**Effective date**

The Effective Date of this Privacy Policy is January 25, 2016.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

We may change this Privacy Policy.  If we do so, such change will appear on this page of the Intellectual Takeout website or in another location as indicated by us. It is your responsibility to review the Privacy Policy each time you use the Intellectual Takeout website. By continuing to use the website, you consent to any changes to our Privacy Policy.
